HaxTalks Subs
Translations by MysteriousAura
I am Guan Fei Bai. I am honoured to fight you, Miss Luo Luo
Mister, don't forget to help me!
How will your Highness be fighting?
The sun paints the clouds a crimson red
Resentment gives the flowers a scarlet hue
I look back at all those I have killed, the sound is like darkness
So please just stand under the night sky.
Who isn’t afraid of the terrors of nature?
Who isn’t scared of the empty sky?
Who hasn’t experienced the stubbornness of adolescence?
Depressed with their fate, and crying with grief.
The youth are affectionate
The heavens can be heartless
Using life and death to break your heart.
Although God may not be willing to help,
All I need is a sword in my hands
To break through the stars
And change my fate.
The vast sky and land are like a giant heart
Affecting my life, my emotions, my love, and my hatred
Like a indisputable fact,
And changing all of us.
I don’t ask for a long life
I just want to live peacefully in this world.
Way of Choices
Relying on the White Crane (Part 2)
I've heard that out of the seven strongest, Guan Fei Bai is the most aloof
Judging by your appearance, that seems to be true
Is there a problem with fighting me?
Of course not. There's just one thing I want cleared up though
No matter the circumstances, I will not dare harm you
I am a student of Orthodox Academy
You are a student of Li Shan Sword Sect, and you want to fight me, a student of Orthodox Academy
I naturally can't refuse this offer
There's no need to hold back. Just fight me like you would with any other student
Let's both use our full powers, and see who wins
Your Highness is absolutely correct
However, the rankings for the students on the Honour Roll are always changing
But before these changes happen, the current rankings are accurate
You're ranked ninth, while I'm ranked fourth
Therefore, it is impossible for the ninth ranked student to beat the fourth ranked one
If we only look at rankings, what's the point of Qing Tong Yan?
Also, what would be the point of the Grand Examination?
Who's stronger and who's weaker...
that doesn't matter until we actually fight each other
Besides, if what you said is true, how did Tang Thirty-Six,
a lower ranked student, beat your younger brother?
That's because someone helped him out
Stop trying to make excuses,
I know that you're trying to cover for your brother
Brother. For this match, you have to concentrate
Don't get too cocky, or else you'll soil the name of Li Shan
Please, your Highness, teach me
Look at that power! Are you not worried?
Luo Luo will prevail for sure
You really have confidence in her, huh?
The sword that Guan Fei Bai is using is intriguing indeed
Actually, I think it's pretty funny
Although his oldest brother Qiu Shan Jun has the tools to counter us,
He only uses a cheap sword no matter who he is fighting
This Guan Fei Bai guy, he looks up to his older brother
So of course, he copies Qiu Shan Jun and uses an ordinary sword as well
Simply ridiculous. In my opinion, there's no way
he can be even half as good as Qiu Shan Jun
Slow down a bit there
The Empress is an important figure
If there's even the slightest threat of danger, it will not be accepted
We only use this for special occasions, it's not dangerous
Is that so? All the better
How irritating
The xiu xing that Li Shan students use is Xuan Gong
Therefore, the power we have is much stronger than that of your Highness
But!
In this case, there's no need to unleash my full power.
If I do that though, it will offset my advantage
Of course, since I am fighting Miss Luo Luo,
I have no choice but to get rid of that advantage
No spells, only regular combat?
That means Gou Han Shi will do the same thing as last match, and interrupt if they start losing
Correct
He wants the last two matches to be combined into one single match!
He really wants to win that bad, huh?
That's probably why he's resorting to this tactic
Won't doing that go against what he was talking about before?
After you!
No, after you!
Why is Gou Han Shi not doing anything?
Maybe he's waiting for Chen Chang Sheng to make the first move
Lifting Earth!
Dong Lin Seven Stars!
Okay
What martial technique is this?
I've never seen it before...
That's the martial technique that the Dong Lin Province created, right?
It's very obscure, so few people recognize it
Nice attack and nice defence!
Chen Chang Sheng is using Wind and Rain Sword of Mountain Zhong
And your Highness is using Falling Rain. This will be good
Who would've thought that Gou Han Shi
will use such rare techniques? How marvelous!
Return from the North!
He changed from Dong Lin style to Li Shan Sword style,
how can we even fight him?
Bright Snow!
Frozen Ice!
Fish Trap!
Bright Snow? Frozen Ice? Aren't those movement techniques?
Bright Snow!
Frozen Ice!
Fish Trap!
What kind of technique is that? It's so fast!
Those moves, it's the Xue Lao City demon clan's specialty!
It's really powerful, defending against it is hard
Thirteen Returns to the West!
That move will let you win for sure, why aren't you using it?
Mister, I don't know how to use it...
Thirteen Returns to the West?
Have you ever heard of that before?
No way. What kind of technique is that?
Even your Highness doesn't know.
Maybe he made it up?
Sigh. If you knew that technique,
Orthodox Academy will win for sure
It's been a long time since I last saw Thirteen Returns to the West
And it's also been equally as long since I last witnessed such an exiciting match
That year, Zhou Du Fu and Tai Zong were fighting at Luo Yang
This match isn't any different
What is village chief talking about? Who's Zhou Du Fu?
And how strong is Tai Zong?
Can you really compare that battle to now?
Well of course, their skill levels are far from Zhou Du Fu and Tai Zong
But, it's just that the battle at Luo Yang..
Zhou Du Fu and Tai Zong were both adolescents
They were only a bit older than these two
Mr. Tai Zong, one of the five saints, his power is almost unmatched. In the chaos that ensued in the Capital a long time ago, he refused to leave the Empress' side, and eventually helped create the Capital as it is now.
Move #7-
Flipped Crow!
Welcome, Mr. Zong
This current match is a once in a life time opportunity to witness.
Missing it would be such a shame
And now, move #11
Principal Sword Technique of Mountain Li!
Begin Golden Crow Sword!
Li Shan Sword Sect technique #3
Flash Freeze!
Flying White!
You're getting reckless
Hey! How come you're not doing anything
when you're supposed to be doing something?
Oops, looks like I won
They won...that means Orthodox Academy won all three matches!
Gou Shan Shi lost to Chen Chang Sheng...
what kind of person is that Chang Sheng guy??
What?
You go, Miss Luo Luo!
If I could use spells...
Your techniques won't be even able to touch me!
If we could really use spells
After our seventy-sixth rally,
I would've broke through your defences
With your current abilities...
It is impossible for you to use spells of that caliber against me
Is that so?
Wait a minute...
Your Highness was able to break through that barrier...
I am related to the Demon Emperor
Although I am naturally able to cast spells,
I have held back, and only used xiu xing methods known to mankind
Thank you for your help!
Admirable!
You are too kind!
The three of us originally wanted to defend our senior brother's honour
But, we were unable to do that, as we lost
However, even though Orthodox Academy won, it doesn't mean much
Since Xu You Rong is not here, it doesn't count
Therefore, your marriage vow is still a piece of paper
Wait, that white crane, I recognize it!
That's Xu You Rong's white crane!
Did you hear the news? Out of all the students from the south,
aside from those intending on participating in the Grand Examination,
Everyone else already left the Capital quietly trying to slip away
Doesn't that mean the marriage proposal for the Qiu Shan family was unsuccessful?
Why would they remain here and be ridiculed?
Yes
What's with that dumb laugh?
Stop causing a ruckus. Our master is thinking about something!
The people from Li Shan and the Qiu Shan family,
they only did what they thought was right
They were uninformed about the condition of the marriage
It isn't their fault for not knowing the circumstances
You're right as always, Mister!
You are my master, if you tell me to do something, I will do it
Whatever your Highness does, I will do as well
I don't think it's that way.
It looks like they're just ashamed of themselves
Wait, that white crane, I recognize it!
That's Xu You Rong's white crane!
Hey, look at that! That white crane has a letter to deliver!
Does that mean Xu You Rong has something to say?
What is the meaning of this?
Could this be?
T/N: Lou Lou is not actually her little sister. This is just how the students called each other if they were the apprentice to the same master back then just like Li Shan students
That, that's older sister!
Hey! Your future wife is here!
Hello everyone
I've heard that Li Shan came to discuss the marriage proposal, and for that, I am very grateful
This is a pleasure for me,
and is also a representation of the love and care they have for me
But, I have my own views regarding my marriage, please understand
Look, Xu You Rong didn't agree to marry Qiu Shan Jun in the first place!
That means the Qiu Shan family and the Divine General just assumed that she would agree, and came here
That's true
The relation between Qiu Shan Jun and I is not like husband and wife, but more like brother and sister
I highly respect Qiu Shan Jun
However, I have never thought about marrying him before
And why is that? That's because I am already engaged to someone else
My future husband is called...Chen Chang Sheng
Mister, shouldn't we start classes at Orthodox Academy now?
Yes, the Grand Examination is coming up
All of us need to try our best
Follow me, let's go study
HaxTalks Subs
Translations:       MysteriousAura, Uknowhu
Encoding:                                      Greatwulf
Timing:                                   TalkedCracker
Typesetting:                           TalkedCracker
Thanks for watching. See you in Season 2
Books again? Does this guy do anything else besides read??
You'll know in the future